Guide to the Louise Seaman Bechtel Papers, 1877-1980 (bulk 1913-1980)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Louise Seaman Bechtel Papers
1877-1980
1913-1980
Bechtel, Louise Seaman, 1894-1985
8 cubic feet
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Papers primarily concerning her work in literature, publishing, and editing, especially for children, and including correspondence, manuscripts, illustrations, biographical information, and published articles and reviews from or pertaining to authors, illustrators, and publishers.
Biographical Note
Louise Hunting Seaman Bechtel (1894-1985), a girl from Brooklyn, graduated from Vassar College in 1915. After teaching young children at Miss Glendinning's School in New Haven, Connecticut, for three years, she worked for a year in various departments at the Macmillan Company. Now known for her enterprising work in the field of children's literature, Bechtel began in 1919 the first children's book department in an American publishing house. Bertha Mahony Miller wrote, "in the year 1919 two important and far reaching events occurred in the publishing of children's books for young people:--(1) The Macmillan Company created a separate children's department; and (2) the President of the firm, Mr. George P. Brett, one of the ablest and wisest men in the publishing profession, selected the peculiarly right young woman as head of the new department."
During the next fifteen years, her work for Macmillan expanded to include sales trips across America, wide lecturing, and much writing about children's literature. During that time, she spoke at a conference at Vassar on children's reading. In some years, her catalogs held as many as fifty or sixty new titles. Three of the books she published, THE TRUMPETER OF KRAKOW, THE CAT WHO WENT TO HEAVEN, AND HITTY, HER FIRST HUNDRED YEARS, were awarded the Newbury Medal.
Louise Bechtel viewed book publishing as a profession, rather than as a trade. Her well-known book catalogs were full of photographs, color illustrations, and quotations about her authors. She was determined that there be "no childish books...nothing which will have to be outgrown." When Bechtel was compelled to resign from Macmillan Company in 1934 because of a broken hip, her closest friend, Elizabeth Coatsworth (VC 1915), wrote: "In everything she was a pioneer with a pioneer's infectious vigor and high spirits. Hers was a great gift of making writing exciting and rewarding in itself, and something went out of publishing when she retired."
Although she was no longer active as a publisher, Bechtel continued her involvement in the field of children's literature as a member of the first committee for the first Children's Book Week and as a Fellow of the Pierpoint Morgan Library; she also served on a number of juries of the American Institute of Graphic arts. In the summer of 1940 and 1941 she taught Writing for Children at the Rocky Mountain Writer's Conference, University of Colorado, Boulder. Between 1949 and 1956, Louise Bechtel worked as editor of the "Books for Young People" section of the NEW YORK HERALD TRIBUNE. In addition, she wrote about books for the Library of Congress' UNITED STATES QUARTERLY BOOK REVIEW, the SATURDAY REVIEW, THE BOOKMAN, THE NEW YORK TIMES, and THE HORN BOOK, for which she served as associate editor and, later, director.
In February 1929, Louise Hunting Seaman married Edwin (Ned) de Turck Bechtel, an attorney for the American Express Company. They made their home in Bedford, New York, where Louise Bechtel gathered her collection of children's books. Louise Bechtel maintained an active interest in the Bedford community where she served as a trustee of the local library; there she founded and directed the St. Matthew's Church School. Both Mr. and Mrs. Bechtel were devoted to the family dachshund, Mr. Nathaniel Winkle, and to raising roses, traveling, and playing host to the troupe of young visitors who came to hear stories and borrow books.
For more information about Bechtel, see A HERITAGE OF IMAGINATION: FOLKLORE FROM THE BECHTEL CHILDREN'S COLLECTION, THE INAUGURAL EXHIBITION. Poughkeepsie: Vassar College Library, 1990.
Scope and Content Note
The Louise Seaman Bechtel Collection primarily concerns Bechtel's work in literature, publishing, and editing, especially for children, and includes correspondence, manuscripts, illustrations, biographical information, and published articles and reviews from or pertaining to authors, illustrators, and publishers. The collection documents both her professional and personal life. The materials, such as scrapbooks, letters, original manuscripts, photographs, clippings and other unique ephemera provide a solid background of the late publisher/editor.
An extensive correspondence documents years of friendship and professional affiliations with such notable authors and illustrators as Margery and Pamela Bianco, Padraic Colum, Anne Carroll Moore, Bertha Mahony Miller, and Katharine Sergeant Angell White. There is also significant material relating to Elizabeth Coatsworth, Vassar classmate and children's author, such as correspondence concerning travel, writing, mutual friends, the onset of World War II, volunteer war work, and family news, 1913-1980; biographical articles on Coatsworth, 1936-1978; and a Coatsworth family photograph album, 1898-1979.
Other correspondents include: Marianne Moore, Wallace Stevens, May Lamberton Becker, Harry Behn, Margaret Wise Brown, Alice Dalgliesh, Thomas Handforth, Susan Hirschman, Alfred Knopf, Anne Parrish, Frances Clarke Sayers, Vilhjalmur Stefansson, and Sara Teasdale.
There are also letters from editors and board members at the Horn Book Company, publishers of THE HORN BOOK MAGAZINE and other children's literature, concerning Bechtel's work, editorial policy, conflicts between editors and the board, and publishing plans, with some personal and family news, 1934-1974. Correspondents include Bertha E. Mahony (Miller), Jennie D. Linquist, and Ruth Hill Viguers.
Other items include scrapbooks of Bechtel's published reviews and articles; typed excerpts from the diary of her father Charles F. Seaman, 1877-1950; family photographs, clippings, announcements, and postcards; and Bechtel's collection of prints and photographs including works by Boris Artzybasheff, Pamela Bianco, Fritz Eichenberg, Dorothy Lathrop, Howard Pyle, Lynd Ward, and Stow Wengenroth.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
The Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library hold the Bechtel Children's Book Collection, which includes outstanding late nineteenth and twentieth century children's books numbering in the thousands, ranging from a mint-condition German children's book from the era of the Weimar Republic--its inserts, pop-up pages, and tissuey windows begging to be handled--to a well thumbed copy of Collodi's PINOCHIO. During her extensive travels abroad, Bechtel became an avid collector of children's books from foreign lands. There are some two hundred or more titles published in France, Germany, Sweden, England, the Soviet Union, Japan, India, and other countries. Among the more familiar of these titles are a Danish edition of Andersen's THE PRINCESS AND THE PEA, and a French edition of deBrunhoff's Babar series. Works of noted nineteenth and twentieth century English and American children's book illustrators are also included: Arthur Rackham, Kate Greenaway, Walter Crane, Randolph Caldecott, Beatrix Potter, Boris Artzybasheff, Dorothy Pulis Lathrop, Rachel Lyman Field, James Daugherty, Helen Sewell, Pamela Bianco, Fritz Eichenberg, Howard Pyle and Lynd Ward are among those represented. Most of these books once belonged to "Mr. Winkle's Room," the library of approximately 3500 volumes in Bechtel's home in Bedford. The books in this collection can be accessed through the Vassar College Library's on-line catalog.
Subject Headings
Names:
Lathrop, Dorothy Pulis, 1891-; Pyle, Howard, 1853-1911; Eichenberg, Fritz, 1901-1990; Bianco, Pamela, 1906-; Wengenroth, Stow, 1906-; Artzybasheff, Boris, 1899-; Ward, Lynd, 1905-; Sewell, Helen, 1896-; Lathrop, Dorothy Pulis, 1891-; Stevens, Wallace, 1879-1955; White, Katharine Sergeant Angell; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972; Moore, Carroll; Sayers, Frances Clarke, 1897-; Behn, Harry; Colum, Padraic, 1881-1972; Parrish, Anne, 1888-1957; Teasdale, Sara, 1884-1933; Coatsworth, Elizabeth Jane, 1893-; Field, Rachel, 1894-1942; Linquist, Jennie D.; Viguers, Ruth Hill, 1903-1971; Seaman, Charles F.; Miller, Bertha E. Mahony; Coatsworth family
Organizations:
Horn Book, Inc.; Horn book magazine (Boston, Mass.); Macmillan Company
Subjects:
Publishers and publishing; Authors; Family--New York (State); Children's literature--Women authors; World War, 1939-1945--War work; Literature publishing
Document Types:
Postcards; Photographs; Scrapbooks; Prints (visual works)
VCL Categories
Children and Children's Literature; Family; Printing and Publishing
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke and Laura Streett, November 2006.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Louise Seaman Bechtel.
Series List
- Series I. Author/Illustrator/Publisher Files
  Correspondence to and from Louise Seaman Bechtel, articles, artwork, photographs, professional notes and memos, and scrapbooks.
- Series II. Bechtel Professional And Publishing Files
  Louise Seaman Bechtel's manuscripts, publications, articles, reviews,and bookplates
- Series III. Secondary Materials On Publishing And Literature
  Bibliographies, book lists, notes on children's literature, and HORN BOOK calendars.
- Series IV. Personal Correspondence
  Personal correspondence and Christmas cards.
- Series V. Personal And Family Materials
  Vassar College materials, Bedford Garden Club materials, scrapbooks, and materials relating to Louise Bechtel's family and her marriage to Edwin de Turck Bechtel.
- Series VI. Artwork
  Original artwork.
- Series VII. Oversized Material
  Professional and publishing material scrapbooks, family scrapbooks, photographs, and children's materials.
Container List
- SERIES I. AUTHOR/ILLUSTRATOR/PUBLISHER FILES
  - ARBUTHNOT, May Hill
    - Correspondence, 1950-1954 (Folder 1.1)
  - ARDIZZONE, Edward
    - Article, n.d. (Folder 1.2)
  - ARMS, John Taylor and Dorothy
    - Correspondence, 1931-53 (Folder 1.3)
    - Christmas Cards, [1927?]-1936 (Folder 1.4)
    - Christmas Cards, 1937-52 (Folder 1.5)
    - Christmas Cards, n.d. (Folder 1.6)
  - ARTZYBASHEFF, Boris [see also Series VI for artwork by Artzybasheff]
    - Correspondence about, 1966, n.d. (Folder 1.7)
    - Christmas Cards, 1945-64 (Folder 1.8)
    - Christmas Cards, n.d. (Folder 1.9)
    - Original artwork, 1970?, n.d. (Folder 1.10)
    - Book jacket dummy, n.d. (Folder 1.11)
    - Wood carving, [1927?] (Folder 1.12)
    - Published artwork, 1930-1967? (Folder 2.13)
    - Published artwork, 1945-1964 (Folder 2.14)
    - Bechtel's notes and writings on, 1934-1941, n.d. (Folder 2.15)
    - Magazine articles, 1965-1966, n.d. (Folder 2.16)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Folder 2.17)
    - Catalogue clipping, n.d. (Folder 2.18)
  - AVERILL, Esther
    - Correspondence, 1954-1973 (Folder 2.20)
    - Articles by and about (Folder 2.21)
  - BECKER, May Lamberton
    - Correspondence, 1953, n.d. (Folder 2.22)
    - Articles by, 1955, n.d. (Folder 2.23)
    - Articles in NYHT's "The Reader's Guide,", 1951-1952, n.d. (Folder 2.24)
    - "Reader's Guide,", n.d.; (t.s.) (Folder 2.25)
    - Article about, ca. 1950s (Folder 2.26)
    - Photograph, n.d. (Folder 2.27)
    - Correspondence from Becker's daughter, Beatrice Warde, 1944-1962, n.d. (Folder 2.28)
  - BEHN, Harry
    - Correspondence, 1950-1959 (Folder 3.29)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1966 (Folder 3.30)
    - Postcard and Christmas cards, 1965, n.d. (Folder 3.31)
    - Articles about, t.s. of, 1963-1964, n.d. (Folder 3.32)
    - Articles by, 1952-1965 (Folder 3.33)
    - Article and memorabilia re: his death and memorial, 1965, 1975, n.d. (Folder 3.34)
  - BERRY, Erick
    - Correspondence, 1950-1972 (Folder 3.35)
    - Article, n.d. (Folder 3.36)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Folder 3.37)
  - BESTON, Henry
    - Correspondence, 1925?-1946 (Folder 3.38)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1959 (Folder 3.39)
    - Article about, 1946 (Folder 3.40)
    - Notes by L.S.B., n.d. (Folder 3.41)
    - Christmas card from E. Beston's brother-in-law, 1939 (Folder 3.42)
  - BIANCO, Margery and Pamela [See also Series VI for artwork by Pamela Bianco.]
    - Correspondence from Margery Bianco (Folder 3.43)
    - Correspondence from Pamela Bianco, 1925-1948 (Folder 3.44)
    - Correspondence from Pamela Bianco, 1951-1975 (Folder 3.45)
    - Correspondence from Capt. Francesco Bianco (Folder 3.46)
    - Christmas cards from Pamela Bianco, 1939, 1948, 1965, 1968 (Folder 4.47)
    - Christmas cards from Pamela Bianco, n.d. (Folder 4.48)
    - Christmas cards from Pamela Bianco, n.d. (Folder 4.49)
    - Christmas cards from Pamela Bianco, n.d. (Folder 4.50)
    - Article by LSB about Biancos, 1926; (2 copies) (Folder 4.51)
    - Article about Margery Bianco and typewritten page about Bianco, 1951, n.d. (Folder 4.52)
    - Catalogue pages for Margery Bianco's book, 1970 (Folder 4.53)
    - Pamela Bianco's published preface to her illustrations for a book, 1928 (Folder 4.54)
    - Museum notes featuring works by Pamela Bianco, 1926 (Folder 4.55)
    - Notes by LSB on Pamela Bianco and handwritten draft of LSB's letter to Francesco Bianco, 1919, n.d. (Folder 4.56)
    - Gallery Exhibitions announcements Pamela Bianco, 1961-1970 (Folder 4.57)
    - Gallery Exhibitions announcements Pamela Bianco, n.d. (Folder 4.58)
    - Prints of Pamela's drawing of Margery and drawing and poem "F is for Ferdinand" by Pamela, 1946, n.d. (Folder 4.59)
    - Christmas card designed by Pamela for LSB's use, 1924 (Folder 4.60)
    - Horn Book Calendar -designed and decorated by Pamela Bianco, 1951 (Folder 4.61)
    - Horn Book Calendar -designed and decorated by Pamela Bianco, 1958 (Folder 4.62)
    - Photographs of Margery and Pamela, ca. 1927, ca. 1930 (Folder 5.63)
  - BISHOP, Claire Huchet
    - Correspondence, 1948-1978 (Folder 5.64)
  - BLAKE, Eunice
    - Correspondence, 1957 (Folder 5.65)
    - Copy of LSB's public introduction of EB, 1961 (Folder 5.66)
  - BOWMAN, John G.
    - Correspondence, 1951-1960 (Folder 5.67)
    - Correspondence about, 1963 (Folder 5.68)
    - Christmas cards, 1955-1961 (Folder 5.69)
    - Magazine photo of Memorial Gate at U. Penn, n.d. (Folder 5.70)
    - Article about, 1962 (Folder 5.71)
  - BROWN, Margaret Wise
    - Correspondence, 1946-51 (Folder 5.72)
    - Correspondence to LSB about MWB from family members - Roberta Rauch (sister) and Mildred Brown, ca. 1954-1958, n.d. (Folder 5.73)
    - Correspondence to LSB about MWB's Memorial Collection in the Westerly Public Library - letters from Sallie Coy, Librarian, 1956-1958 (Folder 5.74)
    - Correspondence to LSB to MWB from Lucille Ogle, Feb-Apr 1958 (Folder 5.75)
    - Correspondence to LSB about MWB from Ursula Nordstrom.Second letter (1952) contains a copy of what may be MWB's last letter before her death [see LSB's handwritten note on 1958 letter] (Folder 5.76)
    - Correspondence to LSB about MWB from Bill Scott, Feb-Jun 1958 (Folder 5.77)
    - Correspondence to LSB about the artilce in the June, 1958 The Horn Book about MWB letters from Irvin Kerlan, Alvin Tresselt, Clement Hurd, Leonard Weisgard (Folder 5.78)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence to LSB about MWB, 1958 (Folder 5.79)
    - LSB's notes on Correspondence regarding MWB, LSB's "notes from talk with [Lucille] Ogle," (Folder 5.80)
    - LSB's article in June Horn Book about MWB, "Laureate of the Nursery,", 1958 (Folder 5.81)
    - Typescript of a speech given by LWB on MWB, 1957 (Folder 5.82)
    - Autobiographical information, publisher's information, n.d. (Folder 5.83)
    - Articles about, n.d. (Folder 5.84)
    - Articles about The Little Island (Folder 5.85)
    - Articles about her death, 1952 (Folder 5.86)
    - Lists of MWB titles - one from Westerly Public Library's collection, one unidentified, ca. 1958, n.d. (Folder 5.87)
    - Notice of Workshop in Juvenile Literature, 1952 (Folder 5.88)
    - Photographs - book cover of Little Fur Family, The Duck, n.d. (Folder 5.89)
  - BYNNER, Witter
    - Correspondence, 1925-1945 (Folder 6.90)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1963 (Folder 6.91)
    - Translation, n.d. (Folder 6.92)
    - Article, 1964 (Folder 6.93)
    - Article about, 1957-1963 (Folder 6.94)
    - Publisher's announcement, 1960 (Folder 6.95)
    - Photos (Folder 6.96)
  - CALDER, Alexander
    - Cards, n.d. (Folder 6.97)
    - Gallery Exhibition announcement, n.d. (Folder 6.98)
    - Articles about, 1960-1964 (Folder 6.99)
    - Articles about, 1965-1967 (Folder 6.100)
    - Articles about, 1973-1975 (Folder 6.101)
    - Articles about, n.d. (Folder 6.102)
  - CHUTE, Marchette
    - Correspondence, 1934-1963 (Folder 6.103)
    - Christmas cards, ca. 1971, n.d. (Folder 6.104)
    - Article by, 1955 (Folder 6.105)
    - Publication announcement, publication info and stage program The Worlds of Shakespeare and article about, ca. 1963 (Folder 6.106)
    - "When the Writer Comes of Age" by B. J. Chute, 1962 (Folder 6.107)
  - COATSWORTH, Elizabeth, J. [See also Series VI for photographic portrait of EJC.]
    - Correspondence, 1914-1915 (Folder 7.108)
    - Correspondence, 1915 (Folder 7.109)
    - Correspondence, 1915-1916 (Folder 7.110)
    - Correspondence, 1916 (Folder 7.111)
    - Correspondence, 1916 (Folder 7.112)
    - Correspondence, Jan-May 1917 (Folder 7.113)
    - Correspondence, 1917-1918 (Folder 7.114)
    - Correspondence, 1918-1919 (Folder 7.115)
    - Correspondence, 1920-1922 (Folder 7.116)
    - Correspondence, ca. 1929-1930 (Folder 8.117)
    - Correspondence, ca. 1930-1931 (Folder 8.118)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Folder 8.119)
    - Correspondence, 1933 (Folder 8.120)
    - Correspondence, 1933-1934 (Folder 8.121)
    - Correspondence, 1934 (Folder 8.122)
    - Correspondence, 1935-1936 (Folder 8.123)
    - Correspondence, 1936-1938 (Folder 8.124)
    - Correspondence, 1938-1939 (Folder 8.125)
    - Correspondence, 1939 (Folder 8.126)
    - Correspondence, 1940 (Folder 9.127)
    - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Folder 9.128)
    - Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Folder 9.129)
    - Correspondence, 1943 (Folder 9.130)
    - Correspondence, 1944 (Folder 9.131)
    - Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Folder 9.132)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Folder 9.133)
    - Correspondence, 1946 (Folder 9.134)
    - Correspondence, 1947 (Folder 10.135)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Folder 10.136)
    - Correspondence, 1949-1951 (Folder 10.137)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Folder 10.138)
    - Correspondence, 1952-1955 (Folder 10.139)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Folder 10.140)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Folder 10.141)
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Folder 11.142)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Folder 11.143)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Folder 11.144)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Folder 11.145)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Folder 11.146)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1964 (Folder 11.147)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Folder 11.148)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Folder 12.149)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Folder 12.150)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Folder 12.151)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Folder 12.152)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Folder 12.153)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 12.154)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 12.155)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Folder 12.156)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Folder 13.157)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Folder 13.158)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Folder 13.159)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Folder 13.160)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Folder 13.161)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 13.162)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 13.163)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 13.164)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Folder 13.165)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Folder 14.166)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Folder 14.167)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Folder 14.168)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Folder 14.169)
    - Christmas and Easter cards from EC and Henry Beston (husband) (Folder 14.170)
    - Christmas and Thank-you cards from Kate Beston Bains (Coatsworth's daughter) (Folder 14.171)
    - Christmas cards from Margaret and Morton Smith, EJC's sister and brother-in-law (Folder 14.172)
    - Copies and excerpts of letters from EJC to LSB, 1973-1975 (Folder 14.173)
    - Letters to EJC, 1962-1964 (Folder 14.174)
    - Correspondence about EJC - letters from Karen Nelson, Librarian of the Kerlan Collection includes cc of letter from LSB, 1969-1970 (Folder 15.175)
    - Correspondence about EJC from Susan Hirschman and to SH from LSB, 1969-1973 (Folder 15.176)
    - Correspondence about EJC, 1949-1975, n.d. (Folder 15.177)
    - Letters from EJC with notes by LSB, n.d. (Folder 15.178)
    - Excerpt from Personal Geography by EJC, 1976 (Folder 15.179)
    - Poems by EJC, 1936-1974 (Folder 15.180)
    - Copies of "One Teacher and One Book," a speech about EJC by LSB (Folder 15.181)
    - Horn Book article about EJC by LSB, 1936 (Folder 15.182)
    - Biographical info - mostly done by EJC, 1961 (Folder 15.183)
    - Material about EJC and her books submitted by Macmillan for the H.C. Anderson Award, including addition by LSB (Folder 15.184)
    - List of Books by EJC compiled by LSB and secretary, 1973 (Folder 15.185)
    - Other book lists, 1967, 1972 (Folder 15.186)
    - Blurbs about EJC's books, 1968, 1971, 1975, n.d. (Folder 15.187)
    - Publicity info by publishing co., 1978, 1968 (Folder 15.188)
    - Articles about, 1961-1978, n.d. (Folder 15.189)
    - Notes by LSB, n.d. (Folder 15.190)
    - Photographs, n.d. (Folder 15.191)
    - Corrected proof for The Peddler's Cart by EJC serialized in Story Parade magazine, n.d. (Folder 15.192)
    - The Sun's Diary Book jacket, 1929 (Folder 15.193)
    - EJC Scrapbook - kept by LSB, n.d. (Folder 16.194)
  - COLE, Rufus
    - Correspondence including poem and thank you, 1962-1964 (Folder 17.195)
    - Christmas cards, 1964-1965 (Folder 17.196)
  - COLMORE, Julie
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Folder 17.197)
  - COLUM, Padraic
    - Correspondence, 1923-1948 (Folder 17.198)
    - Correspondence, 1948-1969 (Folder 17.199)
    - Correspondence (Folder 17.200)
    - Christmas cards, 1963-1970 (Folder 17.201)
    - Letter from LSB, and a copy of critique of a PC manuscript, 1925, 1938 (Folder 17.202)
    - Correspondence about, 1938 (Folder 17.203)
    - Correspondence from Macmillan, 1964-1968 (Folder 17.204)
    - Correspondence to LSB about article she wrote on PC article by LSB on PC, award announcements for PC, 1960 (Folder 17.205)
    - Book lists, one LSB made in 1920s, 1930, n.d. (Folder 17.206)
    - Publicity for PC - one LSB made in 1920s, review, ca. 1920, 1957 (Folder 17.207)
    - Handwritten copy of LSB's introduction of PC (Folder 17.208)
    - LSB's typewritten notes of criticsm on The Flying Swans, n.d. (Folder 17.209)
    - LSB's notes on PC, n.d. (Folder 17.210)
    - Poems - signed and 3 dedicated to LSB, 1946, n.d. (Folder 17.211)
    - Poem published in the New York Times, 1951 (Folder 17.212)
    - Articles written by, 1928-1963, n.d (Folder 17.213)
    - Stories written by PC published in New Yorker, 1969-1970 (Folder 17.214)
    - Articles about, 1935-1958 (Folder 18.215)
    - Articles about, 1962-1969 (Folder 18.216)
    - Articles about, ca. 1971-1972 (Folder 18.217)
    - Articles about, 1972 (Folder 18.218)
    - Miscellaneous and undated article about (Folder 18.219)
    - Photographs - published, passport photo, photos of a PC bust and drawing, 1929, 1951, 1964, n.d. (Folder 18.220)